<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plot on NSW Population Demographics</title>
    <link>/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plot on NSW Population Demographics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Fertility Rate</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/the-fertility-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/the-fertility-rate/</guid>
      <description>A Gradually Declining Fertility RateExploring the Health Stats NSW data for the Total Fertility Rate [TFR] over the period of 2001 to 2019. We can see from the below plot, that whilst there was indeed a increase in the TFR during the 2005-2012 period. There has been significant decline in the Total Fertiltiy Rate in NSW from 2015 onwards. With a TFR of only 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death Rate</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/the-death-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/the-death-rate/</guid>
      <description>A Growing Number Of Deaths?At first glance of the data, for the period of 1980-2018, there has been a rise in total deaths from all causes in the NSW Region. Where, over-time in the scatter plot below, there is a clear increasing trend in the total numbers of deaths relative to time.
And Yet A Declining Death RateIndeed, whilst interpretation of the first data visualization may communicate that the total death may be rising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NSW Population</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/the-nsw-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/the-nsw-population/</guid>
      <description>The Growing Total PopulationExamining the first line plot “Total Population Growth”, we can clearly note a substantial increase in the total population for NSW. Serving as the key driver of the growing total death values explored in The Death Rate.
Furthermore, the notion of an ageing population, is reiterated in the second lineplot, displaying significant growth of the 85+ age population proportion within NSW, with expected further rises from 2020 onwards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
